Swati Suman

Senior Manager

Contact

Bangalore 9066623760 Sweetswati22001@gmail.com

Key Skills

- R
- MATHS & STASTISTICS
- TABLEAU AND POWER BI
- DESCRIPTIVE/PREDCITIVE ANALYSIS
- DATA MINING
- EDA (EXPLORATORY DATA ANALYSIS)
- DATA WAREHOUSING/SQL
- REGRESSION ANALYSIS
- TIME SERIES FORECASTING
- SPREADSHEET MODELING
- STATISTICAL MODELLING
- MACHINE LEARNING
- (SUPERVISED & UNSUPERVISED)
- PYTHON

Profile

Certified in Data/Business Analytics from IIM Calcutta.

Data/Business Analyst with 11 years of experience in interpreting and analyzing data in order to drive successful business solutions. Proficient knowledge in statistics, mathematics and analytics. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective analysis of data.

Experience

Senior Manager • Axis Bank May2022-Till Date

- I work with business stakeholders from deposits (Savings and Term Deposits) under product & portfolio vertical.
- Providing end to end solutions and building analytical products for solving business problems.
- Being at the intersection of data and business, I am driving key business outcomes impacting both top line and bottom line of the bank.

Tech Mahindra April 2020-May2022

Microsoft Bings Advertisement

- Working on Risk analytics duties for Microsoft Bings advertisement platform (Sponsored Search) along with Marketing Analytics
- Visualizing and reporting business required data on dashboards using Power BI.
- Investigating the evolving fraud trends to extract patterns, proactively resolving fraud/fake Activity, Fraud Algo Regression check, Ad hock Tech-scam.

CDM Smith

Sept 2019-Dec2019

- Successfully automated financial and nonfinancial data reporting on Qlik Sense and Tableau.
- Validation of reporting data with the reference of data structure in Datawarehouse.

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta

2018-2019
Executive Program on Business
Analytics

Sathyabama University

2008-2012

Completed Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics and Telecommunication) with 74%.

Notre Dame Academy (Higher Secondary)

Completed "India Senior School Certificate Examination" with 63%.

Krishna Niketan (Secondary)

Completed "All India Secondary School Certificate Examination" with 76%

Tata Consultancy Services July 2017-August2019

GE Healthcare

Fulfilled all data Analyst duties for a marketing unit of Healthcareproduct industry • Identified the best possible combinatory of products which are frequently bought by the customers using market basket analysis • Created and presented Machine Learning models for products to predict propensity to buy i.e. how much the customer is supposed to buy and how much he actually is buying • Created customer segments on the basis of their RFM score, identified the frequent customers • Achieved 25% more revenue than

historical methods • Clustered parts according to their behavior and provided client marketing team with set of parts specific to customers to carry out personalization campaigns, significant risein revenue as a result.

Deutsche Bank

SAP ICM - We analyzed data which includes data of Agents, customers and products of DB. As per the requirements by business meaningful insights were driven by data using differentStatistical tools.

Collecting and interpreting data. Data Mining, data cleaning, Analyzing Data. Predictive & Statistical Modelling. Defining new data collection and analysis processes. Identifying patterns and trends in data sets. Forecasting and predicting using different models in Time Series. Reporting the results to the relevant members of the business using different visualization techniques(MS Excel & Tableau). Working alongside teams within the business or the management team to establish business needs.

Network Rail June 2015 to April 2016

The ORBIS programmer's Asset Data Store (ADS) project is a core enabling project in its delivery of this central 'Data Mart' or 'Data Store'. It will provide the business with a trusted single source of asset information that will be cross discipline and spatially aligned. By providing a single, trusted source of data inside the ADS, this will allow the wider business and industry stakeholders to focus more on the decisions it needs to make and the reports that it needs to produce rather than spending time sourcing, combining and checking data.

Identifying data business requirements. Collecting data and analyzing it using various statistical techniques. Providing organizations with reports that contribute to faster and better decision making process. Meeting with system users to understand the scope of projects . Working with software developers and project support teams.

NTT DATA GDS

Sept 2012 - June2015

State Farm Insurance is a group of Insurance and financial services companies. It is the largest automobile insurer in the United States continuously since 1942 and insures more cars and homes in the United States than any other insurer. Disaster Recovery Services, Systems Catastrophe Services and the Test Center makes up the TEBRS Function that serves as stewards of State Farm's test assets. Test Center provides a centrally managed source of test environment preparation and maintenance, test consulting services, and information on testing issues related to State Farm and IT Industry. Technical Platform/ Skill Set (Mainframe Platform)